I...
detest you.
Hagoromo...
Hamura...
(カグヤ)お前たちが… 憎い。
You...
are mine.
ハゴロモ ハムラ。
My role has come to an end.
お前たちは わらわのもの！
You shall return with me to
the almighty god that is Mother.
(ゼツ)俺の役目は終わりだ。
You two aren't...
(ゼツ)俺と一緒に
母なる全能の神へと戻るのだ。
You two alone aren't the entirety
of shinobi history!
(ナルト)だけが…。
Besides...
moms are supposed to be happy
about their kids leaving the nest!
お前らだけが→
That's what being a mom means!
忍の歴史じゃねえんだよ！
Your teenage rebellion continues.
それに 親離れを喜ぶのが→
Mother is the very progenitor of chakra.
母ちゃんってもんだろうが。
You brats can't hope to
accomplish anything.
(ゼツ)反抗期が長いな。
Naruto, we need to make an opening,
so we can launch the Sealing Jutsu.
(ゼツ)母は チャクラの祖 そのもの。
(ゼツ)お前ら ガキが何をしてもムダだ。
Yeah!
And the only thing that will work...
is that jutsu!
(サスケ)封印の術を発動する
隙を作る必要はあるぞ ナルト。
ああ！ もうあれしかねえ
あの術しか。
aimaina hyouden koshiraete hitatteru no
I create a vague critical biography and wallow in it
seisei saisai nani o mada matteru no
Generation after generation, time after time,
what are you still waiting for
itsunomanika hitori ni natta
I was all alone before I knew it
tameiki hitotsu haite nageite
Breathed out a single sigh and lamented
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosunda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
en de tsunagareba kono hibi mo
Bind these days with bonds and perhaps
suteru hodo koware tenaidarou
They can be salvaged
ayumi o tomenaide
Don't stop walking forward
kibou o sutenaide
Don't give up hope
douka furimuite
Please look back
dou ka kimiyo
Please, if you would
jin jin kokoro ga itamunara
If the heart throbs with pain
kannen no ori o uchiyaburu nda
Break through the ideology that imprisons you
enen tsukihi wa megurukedo
Time goes around for eternity
suteru ni wa yami ga asaidarou
But the darkness within you is still shallow,
not worth throwing it all away
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosu nda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
ai o wakeaeba kono hibi mo
If we love each other then surely these days will
mouichido kimi o terasudarou
Once again, shine upon you
The No. 1 Most
Unpredictable Ninja
"That" jutsu?
Yeah...
Sasuke, hear me out.
I don't know what you're scheming,
but Mother absorbs all jutsu.
あの術？
Your actions are meaningless.
ああ サスケ ちょっと耳貸せ。
何を企んでいるかは知らんが→
How is it going?
母は すべての術を 吸収する。
Looks like they're just staring
each other down.
お前らの行為は 無意味だぞ。
I see...
The power to forcefully drag us all
into this dimension,
(カカシ)どうだ？
that isn't genjutsu...
(サクラ)今は にらみ合ってるみたい。
This is on a totally different scale.
(カカシ)そうか。
《カカシ : 幻術でもない この空間に
強制的に引きずり込む力…》
She's like...
... a god.
How do you plan on fighting
someone like that, Naruto?
次元が違いすぎる。
This could be the end...
あれはまるで… 神だ。
But we gotta give it our best shot.
あんなやつと
どう戦うつもりなの？ ナルト。
Just like we've been
doing all along, right?
これで最後かもしんねえけど→
やるだけやってみねえとな。
今までだって
それの連続だったろ。
Are you serious?
We won't know unless we try.
(オビト)うっ…。
I've been secretly
practicing this jutsu
even more than the Rasengan,
ya know?!
お前 本気か？
やってみるまでわかんねえだろ。
It's worth giving it a shot, right?
俺ってば ひそかに螺旋丸以上に→
If there's a chance
it'll create an opening...
この術を
練習してきたんだってばよ。
やってみる価値はあんだろが。
Fine. I'll get my left eye ready.
Let's do it!
それで やつの隙が
できる可能性があるなら。
Yeah!
いいだろう 俺も
左目の準備をしておく。
Amaterasu!
いくぞ。
おう。
They're making a move!
《天照！》
Take this!
動いた。
くらえ。
Sexy Jutsu:
- Reverse Harem Jutsu!
Sexy-type jutsu tend to work better
on stronger opponents, ya know!
おいろけ…。
(みんな)逆ハーレムの術。
That idiot! Using a jutsu like that
in this situation?!
That might work on me,
but there's no way that jutsu
《おいろけ系は
強いやつほど→
will work on someone so god-like!
よく効く傾向に
あるんだってばよ》
《アホ！ この状況で
なんて術してんのよ！
It worked?!
私は別として そんな術が
あんな神みたいなのに効くか！》
You may be the progenitor
of chakra or whatever...
But I'll bet you've never seen
a jutsu like this!
《効いた～！》
This is the history of shinobi, ya fool!
《チャクラの祖だか
何だか知らねえが➡
The number one most unpredictable...
Don't tell me that
Naruto's Pervy Ninjutsu
見たことねえだろ こんな術！》
is going to save the world!
これが忍の歴史だ この野郎！
I believe that Naruto is
the Child of Prophecy
《意外性ナンバーワン。
まさか ナルトのこのエロ忍術が
世界を救うことになるのか？》
who will save the world.
Perhaps he's a throwback to another age
in the Leaf's Shinobi Way.
((自来也 : 世界を救う予言の子は
ナルトだと ワシは信じとる。
He's more like me than Minato,
and he can be very endearing.
木ノ葉の忍の道で言うならば
隔世遺伝とでも言うのかのう。
Master Jiraiya, are you watching?!
(ミナトより ワシに似て
かわいいところがあってのう))
Now, Naruto!
Right!
《見てますか 自来也先生！》
今だ ナルト！
おう！
うお～！
はあ～！
It's cold! What's going on?!
Ice?
《冷てえ！ なんだ!?》
《氷!?》
It changed!
This place...
Did we shift dimensions again?
変わった？
Whose jutsu effects are
we seeing, Naruto?
Huh?!
Uh, this is probably...
この場所
また移動したのか？
It feels the same as the time
we were taken
to that previous lava world.
これ どっちの術の効果なの？
ナルト。
There's no mistake that
this is our enemy's ability.
え えっと これは たぶん…。
To be able to rewrite the world
in an instant and make it reality...
前回の溶岩の世界に
行ったときと同じ感じだ。
This really is just like genjutsu.
おそらく敵の能力に違いない。
An ice world this time?!
(カカシ)一瞬で世界を書き変え
それが実体であること。
On what principle?
まるで 幻術だよ これこそ。
今度は氷の世界
どういう原理？
She vanished!
This ability...
Can she move across dimensions?
《消えやがった！》
《この能力
空間を移動するのか》
Why that—!
Amaterasu!
Flame Control!
この…！
《天照！》
Thanks, Sasuke!
《加具土命》
Sorry the Sexy Jutsu didn't work.
I never really expected that
kind of jutsu would work.
サンキュー。
This time, we're going
with my strategy...
サスケ すまねえ。
Help me out.
おいろけは
失敗しちまった。
Mother... These two
are quite annoying.
フン あんな術で倒せるとは
ハナから思ってない。
Why don't you split them
up already...
今度は俺の作戦でいく
協力しろ。
and take them on separately?
母さん こいつら厄介だね。
もうさ こいつら分けちまえば？
そして １匹ずつ…。
Where am I?
うっ。
あっ。
Sasuke!
ぐっ！
ここは？
サスケ！
Damn it!
Now you won't be able to
seal Mother away.
くっ… うぅ…。
First, I'll suck out all
of your chakra!
クソッ！
これでもう
母さんを封印できない。
まずは お前のチャクラを
すべて吸い尽くす。
You have nice reflexes.
First, I have to find Sasuke!
This child is fast.
(ゼツ)いい反射神経だ。
So I guess I won't be able to tell
where she's gonna strike from...
とにかく サスケを見つけねえと。
(ゼツ)速いね この子。
どっから来るか
わかんねえってことか。
What is that?
何だ!?
Is it possible that...
we're the only ones
who were brought to this world?
No. The real me is here too.
もしかしたら→
But I can't sense Sasuke.
私たちだけ この世界に
連れてこられたのかも。
いや 本体の俺は
この世界にいるってばよ。
ただ サスケは感知できねえ。
Where am I?
Obito!
Is that you, Kakashi?
(オビト)うっ…。
I thought I died...
どこだ？
オビト。
I healed you.
カカシか。
Naruto!
But...
俺は 死んだはず。
Yeah...
I know.
俺が回復させた。
ナルト。
What happened to Madara?
でも…。
Did you take him down?
No, things ended up
a little differently.
ハァ… あぁ わかっている。
I'll explain it simply.
マダラは どうなった？ 倒したのか？
Might as well tell you guys
about The Sage of the Six Paths
and Kaguya too, and that seal!
いや そうじゃなくなった。
I don't know what happened,
俺が簡単に説明すっから。
but I assume you didn't defeat
the enemy yet?
ついでに みんなにも
六道仙人やカグヤのこと→
Take me to where the fight is.
その封印のことも。
You can tell me on the way.
何があったかわからないが
まだ敵は倒してはいないんだな？
I can't sense Sasuke...
And my real body feels tingly.
なら そこへ俺を連れていけ。
It might be real dangerous
over there!
その間に話を聞く。
I don't know if we'll be helpful
or in the way.
サスケは感知できねえし
本体がピリピリしてんのもわかる。
But I don't want
to fail because
向こうは危ねえかもしんねえぞ。
we weren't there
when we were needed.
私たちが 足手まといか→
役に立てるかどうかは
わからない。
Besides, if we don't bring down
this Kaguya,
けど 役に立てるときに
そこにいないで➡
our world is done for.
失敗したくないの。
The few of us who are left have
to do whatever we can...
We had our minds made up
from the very start, right?
どうせ そのカグヤってのを
倒さないことには→
俺たちの世界も終わりだ。
残ってる俺たちだけで
あがいてみるしかないんだ。
もう とっくに
覚悟は決まってただろ。
That we're all ready to die.
(カカシ)死ぬ覚悟は。
Nothing seems to work...
ハァ ハァ…。
It's hard to believe.
So both your powers and
Sasuke's are necessary
in order to seal away this Kaguya?
ハァ ハァ…。
何をしてもダメか。
Yeah!
But like I said earlier,
I can't sense Sasuke at all!
The ice... is moving.
(オビト)信じられんが とにかく
そのカグヤってのを封印するには→
ナルトとサスケの２人の力が
必要ってことだな。
Over there!
ああ。 でも さっきも言ったけど
サスケが感知できねえんだ。
氷が… 動いてるな。
あそこだ！
She's merged with Nature!
Naruto!
グッ！
《クッ 自然と一体化してやがる》
She's finally showing herself.
What's happening?
カハッ！
ナルト！
That's a form of Time-Space.
やっと出てきやがったな。
どうなってんの？ あれ…。
Damn it! It's no good!
Okay... I've made it look
like I'm restrained...
I'll just wait until she gets closer!
《時空間の類だな》
You said you suddenly
stopped sensing Sasuke?
クッ！
Yeah.
I suspect he was taken
to another dimension.
クソッ。 ダメだ。
《よし 縛られたフリはできた。
She emerged from
a different Time-Space.
あとは やつが近づいてきたときを
狙うってばよ》
It's similar to
my own Visual Prowess.
Can you enter it?
サスケは急に感知できなくなった
と言ったな。
If I resonate my Kamui
おう。
なら 別空間へ飛ばされたと
想像できる。
the next time she connects and opens
a portal to another Time-Space,
やつは
時空間から出てきやがった。
I'm positive I can enter it.
If Sasuke is there, I can bring him back
to this dimension.
俺の瞳術と よく似た能力だ。
入れるか？
All right!
Then I'll go and support
the real me.
もう一度
やつが空間をつなげ→
However...
開いたと同時に
俺の神威と共鳴させれば→
まず間違いなく入り込める。
そこに サスケがいれば➡
I'll need an enormous amount
of chakra to do it...
こっちに
連れて帰ってくることはできる。
since it's not
my own Time-Space.
よっしゃ。 なら俺は
本体のサポートに回っから。
If my chakra runs out
while I'm there, I'm done.
ただ…。
Then I'll go with you.
The real me won't go down
that quickly.
Because I'm strong.
Your Clone Chakra isn't enough.
それには膨大なチャクラがいる。
俺の時空間じゃないからな。
向こうで
チャクラが切れたら終わりだ。
Would it still be inadequate with
my 100 Healings Chakra?
なら 俺も行く。
That would give me
the bare minimum.
本体も すぐに
やられたりはしねえ。
Both of you, come with me.
俺は 強えから。
All right!
分身のお前のチャクラでも足りない。
We don't even know if
Sasuke is in that Time-Space.
But we'll start by getting
into close range with her.
私の百豪のチャクラがあっても
足りませんか？
I promise to find Sasuke,
and deliver him to the real you.
それで 限度いっぱいだ。
２人とも 俺と来い！
はい！
Obito.
Thanks for rescuing me...
サスケが その空間に
いるかどうかもわからない。
だが まずは やつの懐に入り➡
And Sasuke too.
サスケは 必ず 俺が見つけ
お前の本体まで届ける。
Don't thank someone like me.
Just keep an eye on the enemy.
オビト… 俺のことを助けてくれて
ありがとう。
So no more masks, huh?
そして サスケまで…。
フン…。
こんな俺に 礼など言うな。
敵を見てろ。
I'm... Kakashi's friend,
your father's subordinate,
もう 面はねえんだな。
I'm an Uchiha just like Sasuke...
and...
The Hokage is someone
who endures pain
and takes the lead
in front of everyone...
俺は カカシの友であり
お前の父の部下であり→
There is no shortcut to
becoming the Hokage!
There are no ways out for the one
who becomes the Hokage!
サスケと同じ うちはであり
そして…。
The way he forges ahead
draws others towards him.
((火影ってのは
痛えの我慢して→
He makes you want to reach out
when he's about to stumble.
みんなの前を
歩いてるやつのことだ。
I...
火影になるやつに近道はねえし➡
I am your senior who dreamt
the same dream as you.
(なったやつに逃げ道はねえよ！))
((そして あいつの
そういう歩き方が→
I'm not going to waste time
on a speech,
仲間を引き寄せる。
(つまずきそうなら 助けたくなる))
because I'm almost out of time.
But... I just ask that you
let me walk in front of you...
(オビト)俺は
お前と同じ夢をみた先輩だった。
時間のない俺が 今さら
詭弁を垂れるつもりはない。
and die for you.
ただ せめて
お前たちの前を歩いて…。
死なせてくれ。
I'm sorry I'm late.
Have you learned anything yet?
There's no one here.
Just the lower half of Madara's body.
Does finding Madara's lower half mean
that we should
consider him dead?
(ミナト)遅くなりました。
何か わかりましたか？
I have a bad feeling about this...
(柱間)誰も おらぬ。
Either way, it seems he completed
his Infinite Tsukuyomi.
ただ マダラの下半身があるだけぞ。
(ミナト)マダラの半身が
転がっているなら→
And apparently,
it doesn't affect us dead...
マダラは死んだものと考えて
いいのでしょうか？
How did things go on your end,
Fourth Hokage?
嫌な予感もしますが…。
(扉間)どちらにしろ
やつの無限月読とやらは→
I cut part of the tree
to try to free the people
entrapped in the jutsu,
完成してしまったようだな。
but they didn't awaken.
死者の我らは かからぬようだが。
Instead, another branch immediately
wrapped itself around them.
四代目…
そっちは どうだったのだ？
So it was the same for you.
術にかかった人々を
解放しようと→
In order to verify Madara's status,
and find out what happened,
みんなを包む木を切って
救出を試みましたが→
誰１人 目覚めることは
ありませんでした。
we should use his lower half
to revive him with the Reanimation Jutsu.
しかも すぐに 次の木のツタが
絡み取ってしまうんです。
Then we'll make him talk.
To do that, we'd need
a living sacrifice!
(ヒルゼン)やはり 同じか。
How can you be
so naïve at this point?
マダラの生死を確認しつつ
ことを知るなら➡
There has to be another way!
その下半身を使い→
マダラを穢土転生してみれば
はっきりする。
そして 吐かせる。
それには
別の生け贄がいるではないか！
ここに来て そんな甘いことを！
何か 別の方法で…。
You truly are a kind soul,
previous reincarnate of Ashura.
Wh-Who are you?
My name is Hagoromo.
As the founder of Ninshu,
the Ninja Creed...
やはり お前は優しいやつよ。
アシュラの前任者よ。
I am also known as
The Sage of the Six Paths.
あなたは？
名を ハゴロモ。
忍宗の開祖にして
六道仙人ともいう。
kaze ga fui te iku
The wind is blowing
yoru o mata yorokete aruku
I stagger through the night
butsukatte koron de shippai bakkashite
Colliding, falling, and failing
make sou ni naru kedo
I'm always about to lose
warawaretatte ii yo kanarazu umaku iku sa
Go ahead and laugh, I'll figure out a way
gomen ne datte ieru
I'm even willing to say I'm sorry
nakitai nakitai nakitai kurai ni
Until we feel like crying and crying
kirei na tsuki no shita uta o utaou
Let's sing a song under the pretty moonlight
donna ni kuradanai sekai datte ii yo
It doesn't matter how awful the world is
setsunai setsunai rarabai kurai ni
Like a sad, sad lullaby
mune ga kurushikute mo hecchara na no sa
even if it hurts inside, it won't bother us
naki sou naki sou naki sou na hodo
Until we're about to cry and cry
yasashii uta datte arun dakara
There will always be a gentle song
You're The Sage of the Six Paths?
In order to save
Naruto and Sasuke,
who are battling my mother
Kaguya right now...
you must know everything
that has occurred.
Before I talk about Ashura and Indra,
I must first explain the origin
of Ninshu, the Ninja Creed.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Ninja Creed"
It was some thousands
of years ago...